Osamu Ito

Philadelphia, PA | 302-668-6681 | mr.samito@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Portfolio/Website

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Application Developer with experience in Ruby/Ruby on Rails, React, JavaScript, SQL databases, and RESTful API architecture. Background in Apparel Production Management. Demonstrated skills in communication, management, and working with cross-functional teams/departments to complete projects/orders for company growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript (ES6), React.js, Ruby/ Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, SQLite, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Figma, Heroku, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Be@rbrick&Mortar - Github | Demo

Ecommerce app where users can view and buy Be@rbrick art figures

- Users can create accounts/use logins
- Users can search for specific figures by name, and add/delete items from cart
- Mock payment added
- Implemented React.js frontend, Ruby on Rails backend, PostgreSQL, react-bootstrap and custom CSS.

Game Invader - Github | Demo

Game review app which allows users to view and provide feedback/reviews on games which are in our database

- Users can create/update/delete accounts, and create/delete reviews.
- Utilized Ruby and Sinatra to help control backend and server side frameworks
- Used React for front end/client side rendering and interaction
- Implemented full CRUD capability for user accounts/password info
- Added React-Bootstrap and custom CSS for style and overall look of the app

Movie App- Github | Demo

Movie review App which allows users to see a list of movies from our server, to search and favorite movies.

- Users are able to view and add/create new movie details to our database
- Users can add movies to a separate favorites list they would like.
- Utilized Json Server for back end framework
- Used React for front end/client side rendering and interaction
- Added React-Bootstrap and custom CSS for style and overall look of the app

EXPERIENCE

High Point Design

New York.NY

Apparel Production Manager (Hosiery/Legwear)

04/2016 - 08/2022

- Managed, trained, and supervised Production Assistant on all assigned tasks (communication, approvals, and issues with factory and vendors)
- Worked with production team members to oversee all time and action calendars and production/order charts
- Coordinated with design, testing/compliance, sales, traffic, and accounting teams for each shipment and order

Thread Collective Inc. / Billion Tower International LLC

New York, NY

12/2014 - 04/2016

Pre-Production/Order Entry

- Worked with Production Approval Manager to assist with pre-production QC & approvals
- Worked with Sales/Design/Merchandising team to create, update and maintain order details for all customer orders
- Oversaw and helped train order entry team in maintaining and processing order formats and fabrications details

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, React.is and JavaScript program

08/2022 - 12/2022

University of Delaware

Bachelor of Arts, International Relations

2005 - 2009

Japanese Minor (Professional working proficiency)